Are you wondering how to reduce your return rates?
Well, here's 7 best practices
to help reduce returns.
Let's get started.
Number 1: Adopting a liberal returns policy.
A liberal ecommerce returns policy,
also sometimes called a customer-centric returns policy
empowers the customer to purchase a product with confidence
and peace of mind,
knowing they have the option to return it later.
It may seem counterproductive
to incorporate a liberal returns policy
when you’re trying to reduce your product returns,
but a customer-focused returns policy
can actually help you prevent returns,
and boost sales.
Number 2: Segmenting your customer database.
Personas or traits developed by looking at careful considerations
and analysis of your customer database
are much more accurate than general depictions
of high-risk customers.
Segmenting to prevent returns
is not much different from segmenting for marketing purposes.
At the rudimentary level,
you’re just trying to identify trends, behaviors, traits,
and other useful metrics
to make smarter decisions moving forward.
The effectiveness of this strategy
is dependent on the depth of metrics you’ve gathered
and your overall returns and handling process.
Number 3: Incorporating high-quality visuals.
Considering that 23% of product returns
are because of inaccurate depictions of the product,
high-quality visuals
that provide detailed views of items
become crucial to bridge the gap
between the consumer’s expectations and the reality of the product.
Number 4: Customer feedback and hassle-free returns.
Gathering feedback for a product return
can be a tedious process,
both for the retailer and customer,
but nevertheless,
relevant customer feedback
allows retailers to improve the overall brand experience
and understand various defects
in their returns management process.
By collecting customer feedback from product returns,
retailers are unlocking valuable insight
into their products.
Insights, which otherwise would not have been discovered.
Number 5: Data driven emails to prevent returns.
Your marketing team and operations team
are fighting the same war and should complement each other.
Having your marketing and sales team
provide air support for your operations and logistics team
is a good formula for increased productivity,
profit, and reduced churn and hassle.
Using customer feedback
and segmenting data,
you can better identify which products are problematic
and which customers are likely to return certain items.
Number 6: Incorporating customer reviews.
Product reviews provide both considerable SEO
and sales benefits for ecommerce retailers,
but let’s not forget that they also help reduce product returns.
Product reviews empower customers to make better,
more well-informed decisions,
which ultimately lead to fewer regrets.
Incorporating product reviews
is such an effective returns prevention strategy
that PetCo reported that products with customer reviews
had a 20.3% lower return rate
than those that didn’t.
And lastly, Number 7:
Constant analysis and team incorporation.
Although returns are a bitter pill to swallow,
ultimately— they provide retailers a complete view
of their customers, processes, and products.
One of the primary realizations
retailers have
when they start to think of ways to reduce the volume of their product returns,
is how important customer metrics and data can be.
Learning as much as you possibly can
about your returns and exchanges process,
in the top to bottom manner
will arm you with the knowledge to make better business decisions.
Thank you for watching today's video.
If you want to learn more about this content,
feel free to check out the blog
which I have linked in the description below.
If you haven't already,
feel free to hit the like
and subscribe button
as it's free to you,
and it helps us make more great content like this.
And i'll see you all on the next video.